hey guys welcome to this product rule
video use the product rule to find the
derivative of f of X equals x cubed plus
two times x squared minus one so the
product rule is written right here so f
prime of X is gonna be equal to we bring
down the first function X cubed plus two
and we take the derivative of the second
one derivative of this is 2x plus
because of this plus right here bring
down the second x squared minus one
times the derivative of the first which
is 3x squared so that's the first step
some teachers will accept this as an
answer but we can simplify it distribute
the 2x so we get 2x to the fourth plus
4x plus and then distribute this 3x
squared which will give us 3x to the
fourth minus 3x squared and now we can
just combine like terms 2x to the fourth
plus 3x to the fourth is 5x to the
fourth minus 3x squared plus 4x and
that's the answer to the question so if
this makes sense if not I've linked down
below two more product rule practice on
Andy math calm feel free to check it out
please like this video subscribe to my
channel I'll talk to you guys soon bye
[Music]